college english test band four part two listening comprehension section a
大学英语四级考试第二部分 听力理解 A节
Directions in this section
说明：在本节中
You'll hear three news reports
你将听到三篇新闻报道
At the end of each news report
每篇新闻报道结束后
You will hear two or three questions
你将听到两到三个问题
Both the news report and the questions will be spoken only once
新闻报道和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c , and d
B、C和D
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one with a single line through the center
然后在答题卡一上用横线划过相应字母
News report one
新闻报道一
A woman was charged with allegedly violating a rhode island city law against feeding wild animals
一名女子被指控涉嫌违反罗德岛市禁止喂养野生动物的法律
The fifty five year old woman's neighbors
这位五十五岁女子的邻居
Blame her for making the area's rat problem worse
指责她使该地区的鼠患问题更加严重
Newly installed cameras captured several rats active in the middle of the day
新安装的摄像头拍到几只老鼠在中午活动
Neighbors say that it's even worse during the night
邻居们说晚上的情况更糟
The woman and her parents , who own the home
该女子和她的父母拥有这所房子
told reporters that she's being charged for feeding birds
她告诉记者她因喂鸟而被指控
Who would have known just loving animals
谁会知道只是爱护动物
Gets you that much trouble
会给你带来这么多麻烦
she said
她说
It is prohibited to feed any wild animals
在罗德岛市禁止喂养任何野生动物
Including birds , in rhode island city
包括鸟类
Nevertheless , while the woman's intention was to feed birds
然而，虽然该女子的本意是喂鸟
It is clear that rats were also benefiting
但很明显老鼠也从中受益
Antony mareddy , director of the city administration
市行政主管安东尼·马雷迪
Said he saw more than twenty rats near the woman's home
说他在该女子家附近看到了二十多只老鼠
He said it will take months to get the problem under control
他说需要几个月的时间才能控制住这个问题
Questions one and two are based on the news report you have just heard
问题一和问题二基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question one
问题一
What do we learn from the report about the fifty five year old woman
关于这位五十五岁的女子，我们从报道中了解到什么
question two
问题二
what did the director of the city administration say at the end of the news report
市行政主管在新闻报道结尾说了什么
News report two
新闻报道二
To prepare for eventually sending astronauts to mars
为了最终将宇航员送往火星做准备
nasa began taking applications
美国宇航局周五开始接受申请
Friday for four people to live for a year in mars june alpha that's a one thousand
招募四人在火星模拟栖息地生活一年，这是一个一千
Seven hundred square foot martian habitat inside a building in houston
七百平方英尺的火星栖息地，位于休斯顿的一栋建筑内
The paid volunteers will work in an environment similar to mars
有偿志愿者将在类似火星的环境中工作
They will have limited communications with family restricted food and resources
他们与家人的通讯将受到限制，食物和资源也将受限
Nasa is planning three experiments with the first one starting in the fall
美国宇航局计划进行三次实验，第一次将于明年秋天开始
Next year
明年
Food will all be ready to eat space food
食物将全部是即食太空食品
Some plants will be grown
会种植一些植物
But not potatoes like in the movie the martian
但不会像电影《火星救援》中那样种土豆
We want to understand how humans perform in them
我们想了解人类在这些环境中的表现
Said lead scientist grace douglas
首席科学家格蕾丝·道格拉斯说
We're looking at mars realistic situations
我们正在研究火星真实情况
The application process open friday
申请流程于周五开放
And they're not seeking just anybody
他们不是在寻找普通人
The requirements are strict
要求很严格
Including a master's degree in a science
包括拥有科学、工程或数学领域的硕士学位
Engineering or math field or pilot experience
或飞行员经验
Only american citizens or permanent us residents are acceptable
只接受美国公民或美国永久居民
Applicants must be between thirty and fifty five
申请人年龄必须在三十至五十五岁之间
And in good physical health
身体健康状况良好
Attitude is key , said former canadian astronaut chris hatfield
态度是关键，前加拿大宇航员克里斯·哈德菲尔德说
He said the participants need to be super competent
他说参与者需要非常能干
Resourceful and not rely on other people to feel comfortable
足智多谋，不要依赖他人来获得舒适感
Questions three and four are based on the news report you have just heard
问题三和问题四基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question three
问题三
What does nasa require the paid volunteers to do
美国宇航局要求有偿志愿者做什么
question four
问题四
what will the participants in the project eat
项目参与者将吃什么
News report three
新闻报道三
A japanese mayor apologize thursday for biting the olympic gold medal of a softball player
周四，一位日本市长为咬了一名垒球运动员的奥运金牌而道歉
Nagooia mayor takashi kaura had praised athlete
名古屋市长河村隆之在公开媒体活动中
Mio goto during a public media event
赞扬运动员后藤美穗
He asked her to put the metal around his neck
他请她把奖牌挂在他脖子上
Kaura then bit into it
河村随后咬了奖牌
Biting a metal in front of journalists and photographers
在记者和摄影师面前咬奖牌
Has become a common pose for olympic medalists
已成为奥运奖牌得主的常见姿势
However , it is only for the winners themselves
然而，这仅限于获奖者本人
Not others
而不是其他人
I'm really sorry that i hurt the treasure of the gold medalist
我真的很抱歉我伤害了金牌得主的珍宝
Kaura told reporters thursday
河村周四告诉记者
The mayor said the metal was undamaged
市长说奖牌没有损坏
Though he offered to pay for the cost of a new one
不过他提出支付新奖牌的费用
Goto , however , has accepted the international olympic committee's offer of a replacement
然而，后藤接受了国际奥委会更换奖牌的提议
According to japanese media reports
据日本媒体报道
The scene broadcast on television
电视播出的画面
Prompted thousands of complaints to city hall
引发了数千起向市政府的投诉
Some olympians said they treat their metals as treasures
一些奥运选手说他们把自己的奖牌视为珍宝
And that it was disrespectful and unacceptable for kaura to bite one
河村咬奖牌是不尊重和不可接受的
I would cry if that happened to me
如果发生在我身上，我会哭的
Said another athlete
另一位运动员说
Now he sa tacato
现在他说佐藤
I handle my own gold medal so gently that i would not scratch it
我对自己金牌的处理非常轻柔，不会刮花它
Questions five to seven are based on the news report you have just heard
问题五至问题七基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question five
问题五
What does the news reports say about the japanese mayor takashi carol mura
关于日本市长河村隆之，新闻报道说了什么
question six
问题六
what did mayor takashi carl mora offer to do
河村隆之提出做什么
question seven
问题七
what did some olympians say they would do with their medals
一些奥运选手说他们会如何对待他们的奖牌
Section b directions , in this section
B节 说明：在本节中
You will hear two long conversations
你将听到两段长对话
At the end of each conversation
每段对话结束后
You will hear four questions
你将听到四个问题
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once
对话和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c , and d
B、C和D
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one
然后在答题卡一上
With a single line through the center conversation one
用横线划过相应字母 对话一
What's that orange thing on your computer screen
你电脑屏幕上那个橙色的东西是什么
It's something i bought yesterday
是我昨天买的东西
It's a plastic sheet that blocks blue light
是一个阻挡蓝光的塑料膜
I have one that i used to cover my phone screen too
我还有一个用来盖手机屏幕的
What do you mean by blue light
你说的蓝光是什么意思
Blue light includes natural light
蓝光包括自然光
But it also includes light that isn't natural
但也包括非自然光
For example , from computers , phones
例如来自电脑、手机
Televisions , and other electronic devices
电视和其他电子设备的光
So blue light is harmful
所以蓝光是有害的
And that's why you want to block it
这就是你想阻挡它的原因
It isn't that simple
没那么简单
Blue light isn't necessarily bad for us
蓝光不一定对我们有害
In fact , we need blue light during the day to be healthy
事实上，我们在白天需要蓝光才能健康
But too much blue light
但过多的蓝光
Especially from electronic devices
尤其是来自电子设备的
Can harm our health by weakening our vision
会损害我们的健康，削弱我们的视力
And making it harder for us to fall asleep
使我们更难入睡
And poor sleep can cause all sorts of health problems
睡眠不好会导致各种健康问题
I'm not so sure that sleep is nearly as important as people always say it is
我不太确定睡眠像人们常说的那么重要
I haven't slept enough in months
我已经好几个月没睡够了
Because i have too much work to do
因为工作太多
And i feel fine
但我感觉很好
And it's the same for most of my friends
我的大多数朋友也是如此
Poor sleep might be a problem for older people
睡眠不好可能是老年人的问题
But surely young people can handle late nights
但年轻人肯定能应付熬夜
Well
嗯
The research i've read shows that sleep is probably even more important than we thought
我读的研究表明，睡眠可能比我们想象的更重要
And that not having enough sleep can contribute to serious health problems like obesity and heart disease
睡眠不足可能导致肥胖和心脏病等严重健康问题
And all the artificial blue light from electronic devices
电子设备的所有人造蓝光
Means we have to try harder to sleep
意味着我们必须更努力地入睡
Well
嗯
Maybe you're right
也许你是对的
I'm on my computer very late most night
我大多数晚上都很晚才用电脑
And that's probably why i don't sleep enough
这可能就是我睡眠不足的原因
Questions eight to eleven are based on the conversation you have just heard
问题八至问题十一基于你刚才听到的对话
Question eight
问题八
What did the woman do to her computer
女子对她的电脑做了什么
question nine ： what does the woman say about blue light
问题九：关于蓝光，女子说了什么
Question ten
问题十
why does the man say he hasn't slept enough for months
男子为什么说他好几个月没睡够
question eleven
问题十一
what has the woman learned from the research she has read
女子从她读的研究中学到了什么
Conversation two
对话二
As a kid
小时候
Did you know what job you wanted to do when you grew up
你知道长大后想做什么工作吗
No , i didn't
不，我不知道
And i got sick every time adults asked me
每次大人问我
What i wanted to be when i grew up
长大后想做什么
It's the same with me
我都会感到厌烦
And i'm tired of people asking that question of my ten year old daughter
我也是，而且我厌倦人们问我十岁女儿这个问题
My daughter's stock answers are basketball player
我女儿的标准答案是篮球运动员
Pop singer
流行歌手
Mechanical engineer
机械工程师
Adults love that last one
大人喜欢最后一个
As it's the perfect mix of the sensible and the ambitious
因为它是理智和雄心的完美结合
When she was much younger
当她很小的时候
My daughter used to say
我女儿常说
She wanted to be queen of the clouds
她想成为云朵女王
Which i loved that's the kind of goal setting
我很喜欢，那是我在孩子身上
I like to see in children
喜欢看到的那种目标设定
Springing from their boundless imaginations
源于他们无限的想象力
Yes , we grown ups can be tedious and limiting in our need for reality
是的，我们成年人对现实的需求可能乏味且局限
And we teach a very gloomy image of adulthood that whatever our children's future holds
我们向孩子灌输了一种沉闷的成年形象，无论孩子的未来如何
It must be seen within the context of a job
都必须在工作的背景下看待
How utterly overwhelming and dull
多么令人压抑和无聊
When people ask my son what he wants to be when he grows up
当人们问我儿子长大后想做什么时
I have to swallow the urge to say
我不得不忍住想说的冲动
Hey , back off my kid's dreams
嘿，别管我孩子的梦想
We can't dismiss the idea that teenagers have to plan to do something after they finish school
我们不能忽视青少年在毕业后必须计划做些什么的事实
And parents are entitled to hope it's more than simply spending ten hours a day playing computer games
父母有权希望不仅仅是每天玩十小时电脑游戏
But asking what do you want to be
但问你想成为什么
Isn't going to lead a child to fulfilled life
不会引导孩子走向充实的人生
Rather at least to false expectations
至少会导致错误的期望
And a high chance of disappointment
和很高的失望几率
Exactly
没错
We should be helping our kids understand who they are
我们应该帮助孩子了解他们是谁
Even if that means letting go of who we think they should be
即使这意味着放手让他们成为我们认为他们应该成为的人
Questions twelve to fifteen are based on the conversation you have just heard
问题十二至问题十五基于你刚才听到的对话
Question twelve
问题十二
What question were both speakers fed up with when they were kids
两位说话者小时候都厌倦了什么问题
Question thirteen what occupation do adults see
问题十三 根据女子的说法
Is both sensible and ambitious
成年人认为哪种职业既理智又有雄心
according to the woman
根据女子的说法
question fourteen
问题十四
What kind of goal setting does the woman like to see in children
女子喜欢在孩子身上看到什么样的目标设定
Question fifteen
问题十五
what does the woman suggest adults should do
女子建议成年人应该做什么
Section c directions , in this section
C节 说明：在本节中
You will hear three passages
你将听到三篇文章
At the end of each passage
每篇文章结束后
You will hear three or four questions
你将听到三到四个问题
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once
文章和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c , and d
B、C和D
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one
然后在答题卡一上
With a single line through the center passage one
用横线划过相应字母 文章一
Greater internet access correlates directly with improved healthcare
更好的互联网接入与改善的医疗保健直接相关
Education and economic development
教育和经济发展
People living in rural areas
然而，生活在农村地区的人
However , lag behind in online use
在网络使用方面落后
Which limits their access to government services
这限制了他们获得政府服务
Banking and job opportunities
银行和就业机会
Nowhere is this challenge clearer than in africa
这一挑战在非洲最为明显
Most africans live in rural areas that are tough to wire for internet access
大多数非洲人生活在难以铺设互联网线路的农村地区
Now
现在
Some phone companies are trying to introduce internet ready phones into african markets
一些电话公司正试图将互联网就绪手机引入非洲市场
Certain companies have started selling simple smartphones for only twenty dollars
某些公司已开始销售仅售二十美元的简易智能手机
Previously , the lowest prize had been around forty dollars
此前，最低价格约为四十美元
Well out of reach for many people
对许多人来说遥不可及
These devices are powered by software from the giant electronics company
这些设备由大型电子公司的软件驱动
kos technologies limited
KaiOS科技有限公司
Most companies are trying to make phones ever more powerful and capable
大多数公司都在努力使手机更强大、功能更多
But kios when the other way
但KaiOS走了另一条路
It made every effort to keep the essential capabilities of smartphones
它尽一切努力保留智能手机的基本功能
but strip out costs and preserve battery life for people
但削减成本并为用户保留电池续航
Who likely have inadequate access to electricity
这些用户可能电力供应不足
The kios devices offer alternative to the more expensive models
KaiOS设备为更昂贵的型号提供了替代方案
that remain out of reach of many africans
后者仍超出许多非洲人的承受范围
And contribute to the digital divide
并加剧了数字鸿沟
The body of kios phones is as basic as it gets
KaiOS手机的机身尽可能简单
Instead of a touchscreen
没有触摸屏
They controlled with an old school keypad
它们用老式键盘控制
They're designed for three g networks
它们是为3G网络设计的
Because four g coverage doesn't reach two thirds of africa's customers
因为4G网络覆盖不到非洲三分之二的用户
In total , kaios phones are made from about fifteen dollars worth of parts
总的来说，KaiOS手机由价值约十五美元的零件制成
While apples top of the line
而苹果顶级
Iphone has three hundred and ninety dollars worth of stuff
iPhone有价值三百九十美元的零件
Questions sixteen to eighteen are based on the passage you have just heard
问题十六至问题十八基于你刚才听到的文章
Question sixteen
问题十六
What are a number of phone companies trying to do in africa
许多电话公司在非洲试图做什么
question seventeen
问题十七
how do ki os smartphones differ from smartphones of most other companies
KaiOS智能手机与大多数其他公司的智能手机有何不同
question eighteen
问题十八
what are kai os smartphones equipped with
KaiOS智能手机配备了什么
Passage two
文章二
For years , using recycled plastic to make plastic products was cheap
多年来，使用回收塑料制造塑料产品很便宜
By contrast , fossil fuel plastic was more expensive
相比之下，化石燃料塑料更昂贵
Thus , the sustainable option was an economic option too
因此，可持续选择也是经济选择
But now it is cheaper for major manufacturers to use new plastic
但现在主要制造商使用新塑料更便宜
According to one recent business report
根据最近的一份商业报告
Recycled plastic now costs an extra seventy two dollars a ton
回收塑料现在每吨额外花费七十二美元
Compared with newly made plastic
与新制造的塑料相比
This may be because of consumer demands
这可能是因为消费者的需求
They are pushing for more recycled plastics in new products
他们正在推动在新产品中使用更多回收塑料
Meanwhile , new plastic is becoming cheaper
与此同时，新塑料变得更便宜
This is because of a boom in petroleum chemical production from the us
这是因为美国石化产品生产的繁荣
The price increase of recycled plastic
回收塑料的价格上涨
Could cost sustainable manufacturers an extra two hundred
可能使可持续制造商每年额外花费两亿
Fifty million dollars a year
五千万美元
Smaller manufacturers may also be forced to use new plastic to reduce costs
较小的制造商也可能被迫使用新塑料以降低成本
Makers of clear plastic bottles
透明塑料瓶制造商
May also opt for new fossil fuel based plastic to save money
也可能选择新的化石燃料塑料以节省资金
Plastic packaging makers are being pressured to use more recycled plastic
塑料包装制造商正被施压使用更多回收塑料
This is done in hopes of reducing the enormous amount of plastic pollution and the oceans
这是希望减少海洋中大量的塑料污染
The uk government plans to tax companies
英国政府计划对
Which don't use at least thirty percent
产品中回收塑料含量不足30%的公司
Recycled plastic in their products
征税
Additionally , the government is planning to increase the quantity of recycled plastic in the market
此外，政府计划增加市场上回收塑料的数量
This could mean incentives for new recycling plants
这可能意味着对新回收厂的激励
Additionally , recycling facilities may be improved at a local council level
此外，地方议会层面的回收设施可能会得到改善
And recycled plastic could be imported
回收塑料可能会被进口
This would help increase the amount of recycled plastic in circulation
这将有助于增加流通中回收塑料的数量
Questions nineteen to twenty one are based on the passage you have just heard
问题十九至问题二十一基于你刚才听到的文章
Question nineteen
问题十九
What is said about using recycle plastic to make plastic products in the past
关于过去使用回收塑料制造塑料产品，文章说了什么
question twenty
问题二十
what has led to a more competitive price for new plastic
什么导致新塑料价格更具竞争力
question twenty one
问题二十一
what does the uk government plan to do about plastic
英国政府计划对塑料做什么
Passage three at the dream maria business in manhattan
文章三 曼哈顿的Dreamery小睡生意
Naps are for sale
小睡正在出售
A forty five minutes session in a darkened enclosure with peace and quiet costs twenty five dollars
在黑暗的围栏中四十五分钟的安静时光，价格为二十五美元
To be clear , this institution is no hotel
需要说明的是，这家机构不是酒店
This is a nap joint
这是一家小睡店
It sells the idea of the nap as much as the nap itself
它出售小睡的理念，就像出售小睡本身一样
Is a nap worth twenty five dollars
小睡值二十五美元吗
The answer is obviously yes
答案显然是肯定的
Here at this point in the argument
在争论的这一点上
It's traditional for me to bring up all the studies that show the benefits of napping
我通常会引用所有显示小睡好处的研究
But do you really need experts to tell you that
但你真的需要专家告诉你吗
Just look at the world around you at two , thirty in the afternoon
只需看看下午两点半你周围的世界
I've been working from home for more than ten years now
我在家工作已经十多年了
And the quality and quantity of work
我能完成的工作质量和数量
I can do emerges directly from my ability to concentrate
直接取决于我的专注能力
I don't understand how people have created careers without napping
我不明白人们如何在不小睡的情况下建立事业
Every day in about one pm
每天大约下午一点
Everyone faces the same choice
每个人都面临同样的选择
Sleep until two pm
睡到下午两点
And then work until five
然后工作到五点
or daydream and drift around social media
或者做白日梦，刷社交媒体
And at ten pointless meetings until seven pm
然后开十个无意义的会议直到晚上七点
The friends i have who still work in officers inform me their bosses
我在办公室工作的朋友告诉我，他们的老板
insist that they take the second option
坚持让他们选择第二个选项
And that napping is associated with laziness
而且小睡与懒惰联系在一起
I genuinely find it odd
我真的觉得很奇怪
For if you nap properly
因为如果你正确地小睡
It's like waking up from a full night sleep
就像从一夜完整的睡眠中醒来一样
And you can double your day's worth of concentration
你可以使你一天的专注力翻倍
Questions twenty two to twenty five are based on the passage you have just heard
问题二十二至问题二十五基于你刚才听到的文章
Question twenty two
问题二十二
what do we learn about the dreamery a business in manhattan
关于曼哈顿的Dreamery生意，我们了解到什么
question twenty three
问题二十三
Why does the speaker ask us to look at the world around us
为什么说话者让我们看看周围的世界
at two , thirty in the afternoon
在下午两点半
question twenty four what do we learn about the quantity and quality of the speaker's work
问题二十四 关于说话者工作的数量和质量，我们了解到什么
question twenty five what does the speaker say he finds odd
问题二十五 说话者说他觉得什么很奇怪
that's the end of listening comprehension
听力理解部分结束